# J.D. Rowlett

## Junior SQL Database Developer

(832) 649-0460 • <u>rowlettjason@gmail.com</u> • Austin, Texas

### **Summary**

Junior database administrator making a career change into full-stack web development, currently taking courses at Austin Coding Academy. Skilled in HTML5/CSS3, Javascript, AngularJS, JQuery and Bootstrap. Examples of web development work can be viewed here: <a href="https://www.jdrowlett.github.io/">https://www.jdrowlett.github.io/</a> Prior experience includes 7 years in business operations for such companies as Apple, Google and Accenture. Team-player, self-starter, organized, punctual and attentive to detail with talent in copywriting/editing, research and database management.

#### **Education**

- Full-Stack Web Development student Austin Coding Academy 2017.
- B.A. in Communications, minor in History Western Kentucky University, 2008.

#### **Experience**

- Sales Assistant | Don Hart's Radiator Service | Austin, TX | 2015-present
  - Producing market research data on the Austin territory for sales team.
  - Managing all daily shop operations of Austin-branch, cleaning exhaust filters for commercial truck fleet customer-base; transporting all radiators, tanks and filters.
- Operations Specialist | Accenture at Google | Mountain View, CA | 2012-2015
  - Oversaw international shipments of Chromecast units for Google Marketing.
  - Produced reports for senior management on shipping updates, delays, deliveries.
  - Managed inventory and shipping details of Chrome OS hardware for engineers.
- Inventory Specialist | Apple, Inc. | Palo Alto, CA | 2010-2012
  - Managed inventory of all Apple retail goods and reported results to management.
  - Successfully lead the operations team to raise PI score to 98.6% in six months.
  - Provided customer service to guests and wrote daily logs for management.
- Graduate Intern | San Jose State University | San Jose, CA | 2009-2010
  - Library and Information Science graduate student at SJSU for one year.
  - Successfully created a video database of over 10,000 files for the Exploratorium.
  - Wrote copy for and catalogued files of historical articles for History San Jose.